builtwith.com 2019-12-31

# Privacy Policy

**PRIVACY POLICY AS DATA CONTROLLER**

Effective: 1st May 2018  
Last Updated: 21st August 2019

This privacy policy applies to builtwith.com owned and operated by BuiltWith Pty Ltd ("BuiltWith","we","us","our"). This privacy policy describes how BuiltWith collects, uses, shares and secures personal information you provide. It also describes your choices regarding use, access and correction of your personal information.

TL;DR

We collect and store your email address if you consent to us doing that. We store it securely and have a few third parties that need to see that data for email deliverability, fraud prevention and payment processing.

DIRECT COLLECTION AND PROCESSING OF PERSONAL DATA

The personal data you provide to BuiltWith directly is your email address. It will be processed for the following purposes only:

    a.  To provide BuiltWith mandatory account status emails (password reset, email verification, welcome email etc...)  
    b.  To identify you when you login to our website.  
    c.  To receive marketing emails from us (optional consent opt-in).

We may also collect and store your address, if you provide it to us for invoicing purposes only.

The processing of data for the purpose above will be carried out via automated electronic means only.

FAILURE TO PROVIDE CONSENT

The provision of consent is optional. However failure to provide consent for a. and b. above will render it impossible to use BuiltWith internet services as we require your email to allow you to login and enable your account.

COOKIE POLICY

We don't use cookies if you don't use any of the logged in features of BuiltWith.

Our website uses cookies to allow us to identify you when you have logged in to your account.

Cookie Name | Description  
---|---  
BWSSON| Encrypted cookie identifying your account.  
ASP.NET_SessionId| Current session identification cookie.  
  
We do embed videos from Vimeo, they might set cookies; view their cookie policy here - https://vimeo.com/cookie_policy

You can block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block our cookies you will not be able to login to BuiltWith.

SERVICE PROVIDER THIRD PARTIES WHO MAY PROCESS YOUR DIRECT PERSONAL DATA

Our sharing of your personal data is very limited and a requirement for us to operate BuiltWith. All third parties are listed below.

The email addresses that provide consent will be processed by 3rd party email delivery service provider Postmark. See their privacy page here - https://postmarkapp.com/eu-privacy

If you sign up for payment with credit card and/or PayPal your personal details will be processed by Braintree/PayPal, see their privacy policy here - https://www.paypal.com/en/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full

If you sign up for payments with Cryptocurrency through Coinbase your email may be processed by Coinbase, see their privacy policy here - https://www.coinbase.com/legal/privacy?locale=en

If you sign up for payments with Cryptocurrency through CoinPayments your email may be processed by CoinPayments, see their privacy policy here - https://www.coinpayments.net/help-privacy

In certain situations, BuiltWith Pty Ltd may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet security or law enforcement requirements. We may also disclose your personal information as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena or other legal process, when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, when we believe there is a violation to our terms, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request

INDIRECT COLLECTION AND PROCESS OF PERSONAL DATA

Indirectly we will collect your IP address based on the system you use to access our website via our secure web servers logging system. We collect this information for the purposes of detecting and preventing fraud and unauthorized access and maintaining the security of our systems. We will use but not collect/store your geolocation based on your IP address to personalize your experience of using the BuiltWith website.

We use Google reCAPTCHA for fraud prevention which may collect your IP address for law enforcement requirements. See their privacy page here- https://policies.google.com/privacy.

We use Vimeo to display videos see their cookie policy here - https://vimeo.com/cookie_policy

We use Firebase to send alerts if you enable this feature. See their privacy page here - https://firebase.google.com/support/privacy

SECURITY AND DATA CENTER LOCATION

BuiltWith Pty Ltd is PCI DSS as monitored by ImmuniWeb. BuiltWith data centers are ISO/IEC 27001 certified, SOC 1 Type II and SOC 2 Type II certified. Servers that process personal data are HSTS enabled, ensuring end-to-end encryption of your information.

Our short term encrypted backups are stored at Dropbox, ISO 27018 certified data center. See their privacy policy here - https://www.dropbox.com/privacy

Our data center is located in Canada. We have no plans to operate servers within the EU that store personal information.

Only directors of BuiltWith have direct access to systems which store personal data, no employee has access or is able to access personal data stored on our systems.

ACCESS TO YOUR INFORMATION

The personal data BuiltWith stores on you directly is your email address and short term IP logs for the purposes of fraud, security and access. You may also provide optionally provide us your address for billing invoice customization.

You may performance a SAR by contacting us directly at support@builtwith.com.

RIGHT TO ERASURE

You can delete your account via the BuiltWith Pro dashboard - https://builtwith.com/compliance

CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

PRIVACY QUESTIONS / FEEDBACK

If you have questions or concerns about BuiltWith’s Privacy Policy please contact us at support@builtwith.com

**PRIVACY POLICY AS THIRD PARTY DATA PROVIDER**

Effective: 1st May 2018  
Last Updated: 1st May 2018

This privacy policy applies to builtwith.com owned and operated by BuiltWith Pty Ltd ('BuiltWith",'we',"us',"our"). This privacy policy describes how BuiltWith deals with personal information in line with it's business practices as a third party data provider and it's compliancy with GDPR and the Australian Privacy Act 1988.

TL;DR;

We do not provide personal information of people connected to websites in the EU.

DATA WE COLLECT

BuiltWith collects data from the Internet to provide lists that users can access via our premium tools. These lists include -

    a.  Information about websites using specific web technologies (non-personal data)  
    b.  Contact information for business contacts outside of the EU listed publicly on 'team/contact' pages of websites  
    c.  General non-personal information about companies (social media links, telephone numbers, company names)

The processing of data for the purpose above will be carried out via automated electronic means only.

DATA USAGE

See our terms for usage of our data.

PUBLIC DATA REMOVAL

You are welcome to remove your website profile via the [website removal](https://builtwith.com/removals) page.

CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

PRIVACY QUESTIONS / FEEDBACK

If you have questions or concerns about BuiltWith’s Privacy Policy please contact us at support@builtwith.com
